A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Officers, RG 3 FA1797
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1931-2017; 1; 12.65 Cubic Feet 35 containers
  - Hills, Lee, 1970-1997; 1.7; 5.51 Cubic Feet 14 letter document boxes and 1 half-box
    - Finance, 1975 October 9-December 10 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 552
      Memos and report re: investment of Foundation funds and trustee responsibilities and possible liabilities in relation to the investment of its funds.
    - Finance, 1978 January 23-July 12 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 553
      Investment management by BEA Associates, including lists of Knight Foundation assets managed by BEA and updates on performance.
    - Finance, 1983 June 7 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 554
      Report of funds available for distribution in 1980; Budget report of 6/7/83.
    - Finance, 1985 October 7 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 555
      Memo re: Concern over Foundation's investment in Federal Farm Credit Bank's notes.
    - Finance, 1985 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 556
      Investment management report by Cambridge Associates: "Investment Planning and Manager Selection."
    - Finance, 1982 August 11-1986 October 28 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 557
      Memos related to tax issues (excess holdings of the Foundation).
    - Finance, 1988 April 4-1991 February 15 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 559
      Correspondence re: issue of excess business holdings in Knight-Ridder stock.
    - Finance, 1989 October 31-November 20 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 560
      Correspondence re: receipt of Dorothy Knight Trust funds.
    - Finance, 1987 January 1-1992 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 561
      Correspondence and statements re: legal fees for settlement of John S. Knight Estate's bequest to the Foundation.
    - Foundation Visits, 1981 December 30-1983 July 25 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 562
      Correspondence and reports prepared by Eugene Struckhoff, C.C. Gibson, Lee Hills and Gordon Heffern on their visits to other foundations for the purpose of Knight Foundation's Strategic Planning efforts. Reports include visits to the Gannett Foundation, Firestone Foundation, John A. Hartford Foundation, William Randolph Hearst Foundation, Johnson Foundation, William Penn Foundation, Pew Memorial Trust, Kaiser Family Foundation, William & Flora Hewlett Foundation, McKnight Foundation, Northwest Area Foundation, W.K. Kellogg Foundation, and Arthur Vining Davis Foundation. Issues discussed include how to resolve excess business holdings, and role of family members in private foundations.
    - Gannett Foundation, 1974 April 22-1993 April 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 563
      Correspondence and reports regarding the operation of the Gannett Foundation, including its relation to Gannett Newspapers.
    - Gannett Foundation Center for Media Studies, 1982 June 25-1984 May 16 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 564
      Correspondence and comments re: activities of the Gannett Foundation in journalism schools and the newspaper profession.
    - Grants, 1973, 1971 December 1-1974 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 565
      Correspondence re: grant proposals for Youth for Understanding in Detroit, also list of grants for cultural purposes during 1971-1973.
    - Grants, 1974 January 29-December 18 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 566
      Correspondence re: Knight Foundation support of American Press Institute, and the Bicentennial celebration in Miami.
    - Grants, 1975 February 4-November 17 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 567
      Correspondence re: Knight Foundation support of American Press Institute, journalism schools, Detroit Institute for Technology, Detroit Institute of Arts.
    - Grants, 1976 April 5-December 27 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 568
      Correspondence re: grants for the Biltmore Hotel in Coral Gables, James L. Knight Center at the University of Miami, Youth for Understanding, etc.
    - Grants, 1977 January 21-December 20 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 569
      Correspondence re: grant requests for United Way in Latin American, journalism schools for minorities, United Negro College Fund, etc.
    - Grants, 1978, 1978 February 8-December 28 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 570
      Correspondence re: grant requests for joint media seminar with Ford Foundation, the University of Miami, Latin America, Florida Memorial College, Detroit Institute of Arts, United Negro College Fund, high school journalism programs, the Newspaper Fund, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Detroit Public Library, International Press Institute, Urban League, Akron Public Schools, Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press.
    - Grants, 1979 January 8-October 8 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 573
      Correspondence re: requests for support of The Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press, United Negro College Fund, Washington Journalism Center, the Pulitzer Prize Foundation, Detroit Symphony Orchestra, Inter American Press Association, Urban League.
    - Grants, 1979 December 31-1980 December 18 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 574
      Correspondence re: grants to Knight cities over past 5 and 10 years, Georgia College, Lakatos Institute, University of Missouri journalism school, American Press Institute, World Press Freedom Committee, National Press Foundation, United Negro College Fund, Opportunities Industrialization Center of Dade County, State Highway Demonstration Project.
    - Grants, 1981 January 9-December 14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 576
      Correspondence re: grant requests.
    - Grants, 1982 January 22-December 29 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 577
      Correspondence re: grant requests, recommendations on requests from Detroit by Dave Lawrence, memorial to John S. and Elizabeth Knight at the University of Kentucky, request to redesign Bayfront Park.
    - Grants, 1983 January 4-December 30 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 578
      Correspondence re: grant requests (Detroit Institute of Arts, Detroit Institute for Children, etc.).
    - Grants, 1984 January 31-November 5 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 579
      Correspondence re: grant requests (Detroit Grand Opera, National Urban League, Duke University, Inter American Press Association, John S. Knight's papers at the University of Akron), contributions in Knight cities from 1967-1984.
    - Grants, 1985 January 2-July 23 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 580
      Correspondence re: grant requests, including World Press Freedom Committee, Wayne State University, etc.
    - Grants, 1986 January 9-October 30 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 581
      Correspondence re: grant requests, including Florida Education Council, University of Akron (E.J. Thomas Hall), Miami Project (University of Miami), Trinity Episcopal School, New Directions in News project at the University of Missouri.
    - Grants, 1987 February 11-August 11 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 582
      Correspondence re: grant requests, including Inter American Press Association, World Press Freedom Committee, New Directions in News, Benevolent Loan Housing Program, University of North Carolina.
    - Grants, 1988 March 28-July 13 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 583
      Correspondence re: grant requests, including New Directions for News, World Press Freedom Committee, Documentary Benevolent Aid home ownership program.
    - Grants, 1989 January 20-August 28 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 584
      Correspondence re: grant requests, including Miami City Ballet, ART ACCESS (American Federation of Arts), Florida Memorial College, Hurricane Hugo damage in Charlotte and Myrtle Beach.
    - Grants, 1992 April 13-December 17 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 585
      Correspondence re: grant requests for Detroit Institute of Arts.
    - Highway Beautification Project, 1978 August 4-1980 December 29 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 586
      Report and correspondence re: Knight Foundation's support of the state of Florida Department of Transportation's Highway Beautification Project.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1985 June 21-November 15 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 587
      Correspondence re: grant request for books and research projects on journalism at Woodrow Wilson Center.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1986 January 24-December 18 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 588
      Primarily concerned with the establishment of a Journalism Advisory Committee. Includes information on grant requests, the First Amendment Congress and minority and mid-career journalism education.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1986 May 20-1986 December 27 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
      Knight File Number - 589
      Request by Lee Hills to newspaper editors re: their thoughts on directions for Knight Foundation funds in Journalism, and responses. 2 file folders.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1987 February 17-November 25 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 590
      Memos to Journalism Advisory Committee re: journalism grant recommendations, Reporter's Committee for Freedom of the Press, Journalism Education.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1986 January 1-1992 December 31 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 591
      Lists of and comments on members for Journalism Advisory Committee, 1986, 1991, 1992.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee--Newspaper Management Center, 1987 October 22-1994 January 26 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 592
      Background materials and correspondence related to the formation of a Newspaper Management Center at Northwestern University, and reports on its progress. Idea based on Newspaper Operations Center at Rochester Institute of Technology.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee--Mid-Career Journalism Fellowships, 1988 July 13-1990 August 6 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 593
      Correspondence related to the planning and implementation of mid-career journalism fellowships, including the Knight Science Journalism Fellowships at MIT, fellowships at Yale, Knight-Bagehot Fellowships at Columbia University.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1991 May 10 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 594
      Proposals for discussion by Journalism Advisory Committee and results.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1992 September 18-December 31 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 595
      Correspondence re: journalism proposals, Knight Chair proposal evaluations, Journalism program guidelines for 1993.
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Journalism Advisory Committee, American Press Institute Endowment correspondence, 1993 December 13-1994 March 4 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 596
      Correspondence and proposal for endowment to American Press Institute; includes comments by members of the Journalism Advisory Committee on the proposal.
    - Journalism Education, 1976 March 9-1984 August 17 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 597
      Correspondence re: Knight Foundation's involvement in funding journalism education. Includes 10/5/78 statement from the Board of Trustees re: views on journalism education, 10/6/82 letter from Lee Hills discussing the Foundation's policy re: journalism education and schools and Jack Knight's criticism of them.
    - Journalism Program--American Judicature Society, 1986 March 14 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 598
      Memo to trustees from C.C. Gibson re: American Judicature Society and discussion of Knight Foundation's responsibility to train reporters from small newspapers who do not have access to the facilities that Knight-Ridder provides its reporters.
    - Journalism Program--Columbia University, 1987 April 13-1989 October 21 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 599
      Correspondence re: establishment of Knight-Bagehot Fellowship at Columbia University for Program in Economics and Business Journalism. Includes Annual Report of the Director on the progress of the program for 1986-1987.
    - Journalism Program--Harvard University Nieman Fellowships, 1981 June 24-1987 April 13 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 600
      Correspondence re: endowment to Harvard University for Nieman Fellowships in mid-career journalism education. Includes discussions of mid-career journalism programs at Stanford and the University of Michigan.
    - Journalism Program--Knight Newspaper Management Center at Northwestern University, 1988 July 27-1989 September 14 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 601
      Correspondence re: proposal, creation and progress of Knight Newspaper Management Center at Northwestern University.
    - Journalism Program--Newspaper Management Center, 1986 September 3-1987 December 3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 602
      Correspondence re: development of Knight Newspaper Management Center at Northwestern University, including report by John Lavine on "A Newspaper Management Training Program."
    - Journalism Program--"Journalism Mid-Career Training Background Info.", 1986 November 10 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 603
      Report prepared to discuss Knight Foundation's role in mid-career journalism education; includes recommendations for fellowship funding for MIT, Bagehot Fellowships at Columbia University, Journalists in Residence at the University of Michigan, Yale Law School Fellowships, Nieman Fellowships at Harvard University, University of Maryland, and Knight Congressional Fellowships. Also includes background information on journalism fellowship programs at other schools, funded by other foundations.
    - Journalism Program--Michigan Journalism Fellowships, 1981 April 15-1996 October 18 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 604
      Correspondence re: Knight Foundation aid for the University of Michigan's Journalism Fellowship Program to give it the recognition of the Nieman Fellowships at Harvard.
    - Journalism Program--Mid-Career Fellowship Survey, 1989 December 14-1990 March 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 605
      "A Study of Seven University Programs for Print and Broadcast Journalists Funded by the Knight Foundation." Preliminary report, and final report by Jerome Aumente from Rutgers University, on the survey of mid-career journalism fellowship alumni. Final report includes survey results from alumni at Columbia University, the Nieman Foundation of Harvard University Fellowship for Journalists, the Knight Center for Specialized Journalism at the University of Maryland, the Knight Science Journalism Fellowships of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Michigan Journalism Fellows at the University of Michigan, John S. Knight Fellowships of Stanford University, Master of Studies in Law for Journalists Program at Yale Law School. Includes comments by alumni, and recommendations by Aumente re: future funding of the programs.
    - Journalism Program--Mid-Career Journalism Program at the University of Southern California, 1986 January 26-1987 January 26 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 606
      Memo by Lee Hills to Larry Jinks re: mid-career journalism programs, Knight Foundation Center for International Journalism at USC (rejected by Knight Foundation).
    - Journalism Program--Mid-Career Journalism Programs Supported by Knight Foundation, 1990 April 27-1992 March 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 607
      Lists of major mid-career journalism programs supported by Knight Foundation from 1982 to 1992. Lists were compiled in 1990 and 1992. Information includes name of insitution, amount of grant, year of grant, and type of grant.
    - Journalism Program--MIT Knight Science Journalism Fellowships, 1987 March 24-1995 January 30 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 608
      Correspondence re: proposal and development of the Knight Science Journalism Fellowships at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
    - Journalism Program--Minority Journalism, 1975, 1975 November 3 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 609
      Letter from J. Montgomery Curtis re:funding of minority journalism programs.
    - Journalism Program--Minority Journalism, 1984, 1982 June 15-1986 March 14 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 610
      Correspondence re: minority journalism requests from 1971-1982.
    - Journalism Program--Minority Journalism at the University of Florida, 1985 November 19-1989 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 611
      Correspondence re: Knight Minority Program at the University of Florida. Letter from James L. Knight expressing doubt at Knight Foundation interest, later correspondence re: development and progress of the program funded by Knight Foundation.
    - Journalism Program--Minority Journalism at the University of Missouri, 1986 June 30-1989 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 612
      Correspondence re: Knight Program for Minority Recruitment at the University of Missouri, including feedback on progress report.
    - Journalism Program--Report on Major Journalism Grants in the U.S., 1985 January 5-1986 November 10 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 613
      Memo from Jim Batten re: the future of newspapers; Report on major journalism grants in the U.S., and discussion of the Knight Journalism Institute at the University of North Carolina.
    - Journalism Program--Planning Correspondence, 1971-1975, 1971 August 10-1977 April 19 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 614
      Correspondence considering the creation of John S. Knight prizes for journalism and/or writing.
    - Journalism Program--University of Maryland, 1987 April 3-1989 February 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 615
      Correspondence re: the funding of the Knight Center for Specialized Journalism at the University of Maryland.
    - Journalism Program--University of Miami, 1986 May 16-1987 May 11 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 616
      Correspondence and notes re: establishment of a Knight Chair in Journalism at the University of Miami.
    - Journalism Program--University of North Carolina, 1982 September 2-1993 January 15 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 617
      Correspondence re: prospect of a James L. Knight Chair at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.
    - Journalism Program--University of Tennesee, Knight Chairs, 1980 August 15-September 5 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 618
      Correspondence re: guidelines for establishing a John S. Knight Distinguished Professorship.
    - Journalism Program--Yale University Fellowships for Law in Journalism, 1989 July 19-August 11 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 626
      Correspondence re: method for advertising the program and selecting the candidates.
    - Journalism Program--Committee on Journalism Projects, 1971 June 21-1972 March 28 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 627
      Correspondence re: creation and development of a committee to make recommendations to Knight Foundation in the field of journalism and newspapers. Headed by Don Carter. Includes preliminary survey by the committee, suggestions by Ben Maidenburg, John S. Knight Award for Writing Editors.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, c. 1970 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 628
      Background materials and memo by Lee Hills on funding a professional journalism fellowship at Stanford University. Includes history of Stanford program from 1960s.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1970 July 21-August 20 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 629
      Proposal and correspondence re: professional journalism fellowship program at Stanford.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1971 March 26-November 4 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 635
      Proposal and correspondence re: continuation of Knight Foundation support of professional journalism fellowship program at Stanford, and progress of earlier grant made to this program.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1972 March 10 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 636
      Report on Journalism Education Reputations conducted by Syracuse University School of Public Communications, and memo by Lyle Nelson discussing the continuation of Knight Foundation support of professional journalism fellowship program at Stanford, and progress of earlier grant made to this program.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1981 June 16-December 18 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 637
      Lee Hills' notes on Stanford Professional Journalism Program, draft by Lyle Nelson describing the program and how it works, list of Knight-Ridder journalists who have won Stanford fellowships and Stanford fellows who have joined Knight-Ridder after Stanford, letter by Phil Meyer re: creating a mid-career fellowship program to outshine the Nieman fellowships at Harvard, ideas for using the Stanford fellowships as a John S. Knight memorial.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1982 January 6-December 30 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
      Knight File Number - 639
      Correspondence re: the takeover of Stanford's Professional Journalism Fellowship Program as a memorial to John S. Knight, as the John S. Knight Fellowship Program, funded by Knight Foundation. Includes Lee Hills' notes on the foundation's plans and responsibilities in the program, and the will of Agnes Nieman (donor of endowment for Harvard's Nieman Fellowships) for comparison of the planning of the Nieman Fellowships at Harvard to the John S. Knight Fellowships at Stanford. Also includes correspondence re: the planning of a board of visitors for the program, including Tom Johnson and Jessica Savitch. 2 file folders.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1983 January 4-November 7 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Knight File Number - 640
      Correspondence re: the development of the John S. Knight Fellowship Program at Stanford University. Includes Lee Hills' notes for discussions on the program with board of visitors, including outlines of their roles, background and history of the program, agenda of the first meeting, list of the board of visitors, and letter of sympathy upon the death of board member Jessica Savitch.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1984 January 11-November 12 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 641
      Correspondence re: the development of the John S. Knight Fellowship Program at Stanford University. Includes correspondence re: surcharges on the fund by Stanford University to administer the program, list of board of visitors, report of first class of Knight Fellows, update on the program by Lee Hills.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1985 January 7-November 26 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 642
      Correspondence re: progress of John S. Knight Fellowship Program at Stanford, including report on first reunion and workshop of program alumni.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1987 July 18 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 643